{
    "id": "09b5309468444fbda470236eb3889cd6",
    "title": "Infinitive With Or Without To",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I don’t let my children ……………………….. up late.",
            "description": "Let is followed by object + infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "stay",
                "to stay",
                "staying"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Try ……………………….. late.",
            "description": "We make negative infinitives by putting not before the infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "to not be",
                "not to be",
                "not don't be"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I made him …………………………. me my money back.",
            "description": "Make is followed by object + infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "give",
                "to give",
                "giving"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She was heard …………………………. that she was quitting.",
            "description": "The infinitive is used with to after passive forms of hear.",
            "answers": [
                "say",
                "to say",
                "saying"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I would like to lie down and ………………………….. to sleep.",
            "description": "When we connect two infinitive structures with ‘and’, the second one is usually without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to go",
                "go",
                "going"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Rather than ………………………… anymore, I decided to go home.",
            "description": "Rather than is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "to wait",
                "waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I have to feed the dogs as well as ……………………………. the plants.",
            "description": "When we connect two infinitive structures with as well as, the second one is usually without to.",
            "answers": [
                "water",
                "watering",
                "to water"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She needn’t ............................................... any longer.",
            "description": "When need is used as a modal auxiliary verb, it is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "to wait",
                "waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You look tired. Why not ………………………… some rest?",
            "description": "We can introduce suggestions with why not + infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to get",
                "getting",
                "get"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you want to leave now or …………………………… until they arrive?",
            "description": "When we connect two infinitive structures with or, the second one is usually without to.",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "to wait",
                "waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I am ready to do anything but ……………………….",
            "description": "When we connect two infinitive structures with but, the second one is usually without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to cook",
                "cooking",
                "cook"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you feel the earth …………………………….?",
            "description": "After feel + object, the infinitive is used without to.",
            "answers": [
                "move",
                "to move",
                "moving"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}